russia-insider.com 2019-06-20

# Russia Insider Privacy Policy

Please note, this privacy policy applies to this website or our mobile applications (for example our iPhone, android and iPad apps) and from now on will be referred as the “Site”. If you do not accept this privacy policy and cookies notice, do not use this Site.

## About  **INSIDER MEDIA LLC**.

Insider Media LLC owns and operates [www.russia-insider.com](http://www.russia-insider.com/), a service that offers daily news and comments about Russia and the rest of the world.

## PRIVACY NOTICE

Information Collection and Use by Insider Media LLC.  
• Information you have provided to us, including our websites  
• Information provided by other companies who have obtained your permission to share information about you  
• Information about your interaction with adverts and services such as registration, comments  
• Information we collect using cookies stored on your device (for example, this may be a PC, phone or tablet) about your use of [www.russia-insider.com](http://www.russia-insider.com/) and/or selected third party websites. For more information on cookies and how to manage them, please see our cookies notice below.  
• Your IP address, this is a number that identifies a specific network device on the internet and is required for your device to communicate with websites  
• Technical information from your device relating to the service you receive  
• Information relating to the location of the device you use to access our Site.  
Please do not submit your personal information to us if you do not wish us to collect it.  
RI may also collect other profile data including but not limited to: personal pages, gender, age and  mobile number.

## **Use of Cookies**

Insider Media LLC, (RI) uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences and to record session information, for purposes including ensuring that visitors are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements and to customize newsletter, advertising, and Web page content based on browser type and user profile information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set — each browser is different, so check the ‘Help’ menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. Please note that RI allows 3rd party advertisers that are presenting advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their cookies on your computer. Advertisers’ use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not the RI Privacy Policy.

## **Links**

RI contains links to other sites. RI is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site a user should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on RI online services.  
 **Chat Rooms, Journals and WebLogs, Message Boards, Classifieds and Public Forums**

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post public information to Journals, WebLogs, Message Boards, Classifieds or any other Public Forums that information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications.

## **Third Party Advertising**

Ads appearing on this Web site may be delivered to users by RI or one of our Web advertising partners. Our Web advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by RI and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

## **Security**

RI member accounts are secured by member-created passwords. RI takes precautions to ensure that member account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect member information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time. For any additional information about the security measures we use on RI, please contact us at.[[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#71383f373e312324222238305c383f22383534235f323e3c)

## **Sharing and Disclosure of Information  [www.russia-insider.com](http://www.russia-insider.com/) Collects**

Except as otherwise described in this privacy statement, RI will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by RI, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce the RI Terms of Use Agreement or to protect our rights; or (3) to protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service. RI reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in page that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of RI or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest. For more information see the ‘Changes in Our Privacy Policy’ section below.

## **Changes in Our Privacy Policy**

From time to time we may make changes to our privacy policy. If we make changes, we will post them on our site to make users aware of what the changes are so users will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and when we may disclose it. A User is bound by any minor changes to the policy when she or he uses the site after those changes have been posted If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days.

## Visitors’ GDPR Rights

If you are within the European Union, you are entitled to certain information and have certain rights under the General Data Protection Regulation. Those rights include:

We will retain the any information you choose to provide to us until the earlier of: (a) you asking us to delete the information, (b) our decision to cease using our existing data providers, or (c) the Company decides that the value in retaining the data is outweighed by the costs of retaining it.

You have the right to request access to your data that the Company stores and the rights to either rectify or erase your personal data.

You have the right to seek restrictions on the processing of your data.

You have the right to object to the processing of your data and the right to the portability of your data.

To exercise these rights please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#89c0c7cfc6c9dbdcdadac0c8a4c0c7dac0cdccdba7cac6c4).

To the extent that you provided consent to the Company’s processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based upon consent that occurred prior to your withdrawal of consent.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority that has jurisdiction over issues related to the General Data Protection Regulation.

We require only the information that is reasonably required to enter into a contract with you. We will not require you to provide consent for any unnecessary processing as a condition of entering into a contract with us.

## Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us at: [[email protected]SIDER.COM](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#dd94939b929d8f888e8e949cf094938e9499988ff39e9290)

  * 233008 reads
